<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Severn Damp Proofing Ltd | Lime Plastering &amp; Damp Specialists | Stroud, Gloucestershire</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Severn Damp Proofing Ltd | Lime Plastering &amp; Damp Specialists | Stroud, Gloucestershire</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Georgian Cottage Lime Render</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/georgian-cottage-minchinhampton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/georgian-cottage-minchinhampton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This beautiful Georgian cottage had suffered from inappropriate cement render applied in the 1970s. The render had trapped moisture inside the walls, causing significant deterioration to the underlying stonework and internal damp problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The owners wanted to restore the property&amp;rsquo;s original appearance while addressing the damp issues once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-approach&#34;&gt;Our Approach&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After careful removal of the cement render – a painstaking process to avoid damaging the soft limestone beneath – we allowed the walls to dry out naturally over several weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who We Are&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re Severn Damp Proofing Ltd – a small team of experienced craftsmen based in Stroud, Gloucestershire. We specialise in two things: &lt;strong&gt;traditional lime plastering&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;professional damp proofing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-story&#34;&gt;Our Story&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With over 35 years of combined experience in the trade, we&amp;rsquo;ve built our reputation on doing things properly. No shortcuts, no bodge jobs – just quality craftsmanship that stands the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve worked on hundreds of properties across Gloucestershire and the Cotswolds, from modest cottages to grand country houses. Every project receives the same attention to detail, because that&amp;rsquo;s simply how we work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damp Proofing Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/services/damp-proofing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/services/damp-proofing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;comprehensive-damp-solutions&#34;&gt;Comprehensive Damp Solutions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Damp isn&amp;rsquo;t just unsightly – it damages your property and can affect your health. But before reaching for a &amp;ldquo;solution,&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand what&amp;rsquo;s actually causing the problem. That&amp;rsquo;s where we start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-damp&#34;&gt;Understanding Damp&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all damp is the same, and the wrong treatment can be worse than no treatment at all. We see countless properties where previous &amp;ldquo;damp proofing&amp;rdquo; has actually made things worse by trapping moisture inside the walls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lime Plastering &amp; Damp Proofing in Cirencester</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/areas/cirencester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/areas/cirencester/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lime-plastering--damp-proofing-specialists-serving-cirencester&#34;&gt;Lime Plastering &amp;amp; Damp Proofing Specialists Serving Cirencester&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cirencester, the historic capital of the Cotswolds, is surrounded by some of England&amp;rsquo;s most beautiful villages. From Roman foundations to Georgian elegance, this area&amp;rsquo;s buildings span two millennia of architectural heritage – and they deserve specialist care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cirencester-areas-unique-building-heritage&#34;&gt;The Cirencester Area&amp;rsquo;s Unique Building Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As one of Britain&amp;rsquo;s oldest towns, Cirencester and its surrounding villages contain an exceptional concentration of listed buildings and heritage properties. The local Cotswold limestone, quarried from sites around the area, gives these buildings their distinctive honey-coloured appearance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lime Plastering &amp; Damp Proofing in Stroud</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/areas/stroud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/areas/stroud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-local-lime-plastering--damp-proofing-experts-in-stroud&#34;&gt;Your Local Lime Plastering &amp;amp; Damp Proofing Experts in Stroud&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based right here in Stroud, we&amp;rsquo;ve spent decades working on the beautiful period properties that make this area so special. From the grand wool merchant houses of Painswick to the traditional weavers&amp;rsquo; cottages dotted around the valleys, we understand what makes these buildings tick.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-stroud-properties-need-specialist-care&#34;&gt;Why Stroud Properties Need Specialist Care&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Stroud valleys are home to some of Gloucestershire&amp;rsquo;s finest heritage buildings. Many were built using local Cotswold stone and traditional lime mortars – materials that have allowed these structures to stand for centuries. The key to their longevity? They can breathe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lime Plastering &amp; Damp Proofing in Tetbury</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/areas/tetbury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/areas/tetbury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lime-plastering--damp-proofing-experts-for-tetbury--surrounds&#34;&gt;Lime Plastering &amp;amp; Damp Proofing Experts for Tetbury &amp;amp; Surrounds&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tetbury&amp;rsquo;s picture-perfect market town centre and the grand estates of the surrounding countryside represent some of the finest traditional architecture in the Cotswolds. These buildings deserve craftsmen who understand their unique requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tetburys-architectural-heritage&#34;&gt;Tetbury&amp;rsquo;s Architectural Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the iconic Market House to the wool merchants&amp;rsquo; houses lining Long Street, Tetbury&amp;rsquo;s buildings tell the story of centuries of prosperity and careful stewardship. The surrounding villages – many centred around historic manor houses and farmsteads – continue this tradition of quality construction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lime Plastering Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/services/lime-plastering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/services/lime-plastering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;traditional-lime-plastering-for-heritage-properties&#34;&gt;Traditional Lime Plastering for Heritage Properties&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lime plastering isn&amp;rsquo;t just another building trade – it&amp;rsquo;s a craft that has protected buildings for thousands of years. Unlike modern cement-based products, lime allows your walls to breathe, preventing the moisture build-up that causes so many problems in old buildings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-lime-matters&#34;&gt;Why Lime Matters&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the 20th century, virtually every building was constructed using lime. The walls, the renders, the mortars – all lime-based. These materials worked in harmony with traditional construction methods, allowing moisture to pass through the building fabric rather than trapping it inside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
